Levi Smith

Tulsa, OK (918) 232-4434

<u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>LCSmith87@gmail.com</u>

SUMMARY

Dedicated problem solver with over 14 years of experience with 10 years in technical roles, 8 years of digital media experience in B2B industries specializing in web production, project management, sales support, and ad operations, and over 4 years leading and mentoring teams to succeed.

Skills: Project Management, Communication, Problem Solving, Web Production, Leadership, Sales Support & Customer Service, Adaptability, Digital Media, Ad Operations, Web Development, Content Management Systems

Software & Programming: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, C#, SQL, GraphQL, WordPress, Adobe Experience Manager, Google Analytics, Filemaker, Photoshop, DFP, AppNexus, Tealium, Google Tag Manager, Git, JIRA, PowerPoint, Excel, ReactJS, GatsbyJS

WORK HISTORY

Management & Technical

Clarion Events - Director of SEO & Analytics

Feb 2020- Present

Handle the day to day SEO efforts, strategy, and roadmap for 14 different media and event websites, as well as the ongoing training and analytics around our KPIs.

- Created and implemented a detailed roadmap for pushing our SEO efforts forward.
- Designed our KPIs and analytics strategy around the metrics that push our websites forward
- Developed ongoing training for editors and marketers to implement SEO best practices in their day to day.

Clarion Events - Sr. Digital Media Manager

Feb 2019 - Feb 2020

Manage the day to day of our website and advertising operations. Developed advertising templates, traffic ads, work with advertisers to improve their ad campaign

- Helped facilitate the migration of 14 websites from AEM to WordPress
- Acted as a technical liaison for all things WordPress
- Oversaw the technical aspects of a migration from OpenAd Stream to GAM

BMC Software - Sr. Manager of Web Operations (Remote)

Jul 2018 – Feb 2019

Lead a global team of 9 to manage, improve, and iterate on bmc.com, which includes project management, website operations, and governance functions.

- Created a modern project management framework in order to standardize projects, ensure quality, and deliver on-time and outstanding results for over 40 high-priority projects a quarter.
- Collaborate across marketing, IT, sales, and product lines to ensure projects are on time, in scope, and within budget.
- Monitor daily website operations activity and oversee 100's of website edits each month.
- Manage the internationalization efforts in order to translate entire site to over 30 different ccTLDS with an annual budget of \$30k.
- Led a company-wide interlock presentation on the benefits of the centralized publishing model and how to oversee a modern enterprise website.

PennWell - Website Project Manager (Tulsa OK/Remote)

Apr 2016 – Jul 2018

Manage the ongoing projects to ensure on time completion and outstanding results for over 30 websites with 10,000+ articles and pages that generate \$30 million in annual revenue.

- Created more standardized and streamlined processes to model a more efficient workflow and consistent websites, leading the team to complete over 90 tickets a month
- Developed a browser extension to help stakeholders better navigate the Content Management System and grew it to over 50 daily active users.
- Performed as technical lead in charge of developing 100s of custom pages and implementing custom JavaScript libraries
- Helped initiative for switching sites to SSL and making improvements on security
- Developed a custom Python script for appending metadata to 100s of images each month in which reduced manual work by over 2 hours each week

PennWell - Manager, Ad Tech / Ad Operations (Tulsa OK)

Sep 2013 - Apr 2016

Led the team of 4 responsible for executing 1000+ digital advertising campaigns each month for hundreds of different advertisers.

- Increased sales and sales responses by collaborating with sales to create and maintain rate card specifications, media kits, and technical sales sheets
- Developed and maintained a complex Filemaker application and database for managing advertising campaigns that total more than \$10 million in annual revenue with over a million database records
- Improved and standardized processes by developing a web app using Filemaker and PHP for automating certain ad operations procedures and hooking into ad server API's
- Created and improved many rich media ad templates using modern HTML/Javascript standards
- Steered the strategy of digital advertising towards programmatic and native and improved standards of current ad products

Technical & Customer Service

PennWell - Digital Media Advertising Support Specialist - Tulsa OK

Dec 2011 – Sep 2013

Collaborated with sales to implement, coordinate, and improve 1000+ advertising campaigns each month with over \$5 million in revenue.

- Increased production workflow, of a team of 3, by over 20+% by simplifying processes and reducing overlap and rework
- Earned a 99% percent in customer satisfaction while maintaining under 2% of errors and make-goods
- Managed the relationships of over 100 advertisers by providing outstanding customer service, supporting issues quickly and effectively, and completing RFI's thoroughly

TRAINING & EDUCATION

Tulsa Community College

Tulsa OK

- Digital Media Media Design, 2008 2009
- Obtained over 50 credit hours
- Achieved certifications in Adobe Dreamweaver, Photoshop, and Flash
- Gained extensive knowledge of web design and digital media